thenorthface.co.uk 2019-08-18

# Privacy Policy Highlights

Read our full privacy policy

## SCOPE

This privacy policy applies to the collection and use of customers' and https://www.thenorthface.co.uk visitors' personal data by VF International Sagl (that operates this website and is responsible for VF marketing activities) and by VF local subsidiaries (that are responsible for the purchases you make with them online or in store). 

more info

## WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT

We collect your personal data that you provide to us when you:

· use this web+site (e.g., opening an account, uploading content, etc.)

· take part/subscribe to our marketing activities (e.g., newsletters, loyalty programs, etc.)

· purchase products from us (online or in store)

· contact our customer-service

We also automatically collect certain information about your use of this website (e.g., IP address, number of visits, time spent, etc.) and aggregate them to measure and enhance the functioning of the website.

more info

## WHY WE USE YOUR INFORMATION FOR

We collect and process your personal data in order to:

· manage this website

· send you marketing materials, allow you to participate in promotions, conduct customer surveys and profiling activities

· complete and manage your purchases, operate our customer-service and respond to your requests

· improve our products and services

We do not sell or share your personal data to marketers outside of the VF group.

more info

## HOW LONG WE KEEP YOUR INFORMATION

We only keep your personal data for so long as necessary to achieve these purposes. This may be up to 10 years after the end of the contractual relationship with you (statute of limitation for legal claims in most EEA countries), unless a shorter or longer retention period applies under applicable data protection laws.

more info

## PARTIES WITH WHICH WE SHARE YOUR INFORMATION

The VF local subsidiary from which you purchase products shares your personal data with VF International Sagl for marketing purposes (but, when required by law, we ask your consent before doing so).

We also share your personal data with:

· other VF entities and third party providers that help us operate this website and provide our products and services (these recipients act on our behalf and under our instructions only);

· third parties in case of judicial processes, request by courts or authorities, other legal obligation, to defend our rights, or in case of merger, acquisition, or assets transfer.

Some of these recipients are located outside the EEA, but we ensure that your personal data remain at all times adequately protected (if the country of destination is not one that the EU Commission considers offers an adequate level of protection, we cover the data transfer by appropriate safeguards).

more info 

## NECESSARY v. OPTIONAL INFORMATION

Some of your personal data are necessary to complete your purchase or to provide the service that you request from us. If you refuse to provide these personal data, it would make it impossible for us to complete the purchase or provide the requested service.

Providing personal data for survey, marketing and other profiling purposes is however optional. If you refuse, this will not have any impact on the purchase or the provision of the service you requested.

more info

## YOUR RIGHTS

You may, at any moment, exercise your rights under data protection law, including (when applicable) your right of access, rectification, restriction, erasure, opposition (including objecting, at any time and for free, to the processing of your personal data for direct marketing), right to portability and your right to withdraw consent.  You also have the right to lodge a complaint with the competent supervisory authority.

more info

## WE USE COOKIES

Certain information is gathered on this website by cookies and other tracking technologies. You can manage your cookie preferences through our tool or through your browser.

more info

## THIRD PARTY LINKS

The website may contain links to other sites, as well as objects or elements controlled by third parties. We do not have access nor control these elements and disclaim any responsibility for such third party websites.

more info

## HOW TO CONTACT US

For any query or request relating to  our use of your personal data, or to exercise your rights, you may contact our Privacy Office at [privacy_europe@vfc.com](mailto:privacy_europe@vfc.com).
